In this video, we're going to take a
look at posting setup in Dynamics SL and
compare that to the experience of
defining posting groups in Business
Central.
Setting up default posting accounts in
SL helps simplify and reduce errors and
inconsistencies when posting
transactions.
Once the accounts are set up, they will
default on transaction entry windows.
In this example, we have defined
accounts for default accounts in AP
setup and AR setup, including invoicing
and payment accounts.
If I go to one of the customers in SL, I
can see that the customer is assigned to
a specific class.
And in that class, we have categorized
those transactions posted from customers
in this class to use different accounts.
In rare cases, you can define more
granularly and enter in unique accounts
for individual customers.
Similar logic can be applied to vendors
and items.
Now, let's look at Business Central and
how we configure posting accounts and
define defaults.
Business Central uses posting groups to
tie customers, vendors, and items to GL
accounts.
There are several different types of
posting groups in Business Central.
Business posting groups focus on who you
are buying and selling to.
Product posting groups focus on what you
are buying and selling.
Let's take a closer look in the business
posting groups.
You can group master data like customers
into regions, segments, industries, or
however your business wants to
categorize sales and purchases for
reporting.
Product posting groups focus on what you
sell or buy.
You may distinguish on product lines or
by use like manufacturing, retail, or
services.
General posting setup is where you will
put these two concepts together,
combining the who with the what.
In this example, we are indicating
who are enterprise customers with the
what, which is equipment, and then we
can define the sales, cost of goods sold
account, and other relevant accounts.
Now, let's look at a customer and see
where we can assign these posting
groups.
On my customer card, I can see I have
assigned the enterprise general business
posting group and the customer posting
domestic.
The customer group is where you define
your AR and discount accounts.
Now, let's create a sales invoice and
see how the accounts all get defaulted
into the transactions.
Similar to the customer posting groups,
all items also have an inventory posting
group.
The inventory posting group is where you
can define accounts based on item
classification and location.
Finally, let's preview posting for the
invoice so we can see the GL accounts
that will be used when posting.
You can see the inventory account is
pulled from the inventory posting group.
We just saw the cost of goods sold and
sales accounts are being pulled from the
posting setup where we define the what
from the product posting group
and the who from the general business
posting.
Finally, the accounts receivable account
from my customer posting group.
And that's a look at how posting groups
can be set up in Business Central with
similar posting outcomes as SL.
To learn more about Business Central,
see the following resources.